<article title="Interplanetary missions - Catalog" current="orbits">
	<heading>Orbits</heading>
	<content>
		<section>
			<side>
				<heading>Launch window</heading>
				<p>To Neptune:</p>
				<list>
					<p><pageref id="win-ejn">swinging by Jupiter</pageref></p>
					<p><pageref id="win-esn">swinging by Saturn</pageref></p>
					<p><pageref id="win-ejsn">swinging by Jupiter and Saturn</pageref></p>
				</list>
			</side>
			<p>As the alignment of the targeted bodies changes in time,
			interplanetary orbits that depend of a particular configuration of
			the planets are only suitable at some limited periods 
			of time. These allowed periods are called <em>launch windows</em>. 
			During a <em>launch window</em> the change on the alignment of
			the bodies is sufficiently small to give similar fitting 
			orbits. For different <em>launch windows</em> instead, fitting
			orbits may be substantially different.</p>
			<p>Since all planets have periodic orbits, the configuration of
			targeted bodies is quasi-repetitive. In a simple Earth-Planet orbit,
			by example, the repetition of the configuration is based on the 
			synodic period (see <wiki term="Orbital_Period">orbital period</wiki>) 
			of the planet. See also <wiki term="Launch_window">Launch window</wiki>.</p>
		</section>
		<section>
			<side>
				<heading>By &#916;V</heading>
				<list>
					<p><pageref id="dvj2013">To Jupiter</pageref></p>
				</list>
			</side>
			<p>One of the most important properties of an orbit is the cost for reaching it.
			In general, on board engines are used to drive the spacecraft to its target by doing 
			short-time impulses.
			These short impulses can be considered as a first approach like instantaneous velocity
			changes. The module (the scalar quantity) of the velocity change is called
			&#916;V. This quantity determines the amount of fuel needed to achieve the maneuver. 
			</p>
			<p>In these examples, the &#916;V for an initial orbit insertion is shown. The 
			maneuver consists of a transfer from a circular Earth stationary orbit (not shown)
			to the selected orbit.  
			</p>
		</section>
		<section>
			<side>
				<heading>Exotic</heading>
				<list>
					<p><pageref id="exotic-esjm-retro">Saturn-Jupiter-Mars with a final elliptical retrograde orbit.</pageref></p>
				</list>
			</side>
			<p></p>
		</section>
	</content>
</article>
